日本語字幕仕上げ：miraku  光荣字幕组（www.koeigame.cn）
You must really love your job.
ホント　お前仕事好きなのな
味方のゴルが決まったら
The entire board will cheer when we score a goal.
会社ぐるみで大喜びすんのよ
And when we're on a losing streak, it feels like you're attending a wake.
連敗でもしたら
お通夜みたいに全員で暗くなっちゃって
It's the only workplace where you can feel so much passion.
こんな　こんな情熱注げて感動できる職場
どこ探したって見つからないわよ
There's no place like this anywhere else.
So says the person who collapsed.
ぶっ倒れてたヤツが何を偉そうに
Th-That...
それは…
９０分間　全力疾走できる選手なんているわけねえだろ
No player can sprint constantly for 90 minutes.
Balance is required for everything.
偉そうに
Look who's talking.
Tsubaki, will you play well in the next one too?
椿…次もやってくれっかなぁ
ちょっと　あんた！うっ
Hey, you!
また　そんなもん読んでニタニタして！
Why are you still grinning while you're reading that thing?
仕事しなさいよ　仕事！
You should be working!
だ　だって　今　客いねえしよあたしはね
B-But we don't have any customers right now.
I'm talking about your attitude!
姿勢の話をしてんのよ！
そうだよ　父ちゃん
That's right, dad.
You too, Kota?
な　何だよ　コタまで
選手たちはそんなに浮かれてないよ
The players are not having an easy time.
Don't be fooled!
勘違いしちゃ駄目だかんね！
はあ？　なんだよ　もう
What the?
Goro!
吾郎！
写真屋の山さんサポタやってくれるってよ！
Yama from the photo lab agreed to join us!
ほっ　本当かよ！
Really?!
I have been interested for quite some time now...
前から　ちょっと興味ありまして
やろう！一緒にやろう！
Alright! Let's do it together!
Hey, you!
ちょっと　あんた！
Dad!
父ちゃん！
I just mentioned...
言ったそばから！
浮かれんなってば！
Don't be overly cheerful!
First, I'll teach you our chant!
まずは　チャント教えるよ
Chant?
ちゃんと？
It's a cheer to support the team. The rhythm's very important.
チャントってのは応援歌でよリ
ズム感が大事なんだ
Don't ignore us!
人の話を聞け！
ズム感ズム感
United we stand,Fly a flag 風を受け止めて
United we stand, Fly a flag!
kaze o uketomete
風を受け止めて
Let the wind blow through you
United we stand,Fly a flag たなびけ勝利のflag
United we stand, Fly a flag!
tanabike shouri no flag
たなびけ勝利の flag
Let the victory flag trail in the wind
遥かなゴールを信じて 走り続けていて
haruka na gooru o shinjite
遥かなゴールを信じて
Believe in the goal that lies in wait and keep running
hashiri tsuzuketeke
走り続けてけ
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ 降り注げ光よ
hibi yume tsumugu monotachi e furisosoge hikari yo
日々夢紡ぐ者達へ降り注げ光よ
Let light pour down upon the weaver of dreams
汗は裏切らないって 唇噛み締め
ase wa uragiranaitte kuchibiru kamishime
汗は裏切らないって唇噛み締め
Your sweat won't betray you, so bite down on your lips
何度も立ち上がり 大地を駆け抜ける
nandomo tachiagari daichi o kakenukeru
何度も立ち上がり大地を駆け抜ける
And stand back up again and again as you dash across the earth
夢に終わりはないって 目を輝かせ
yume ni owari wa naitte me o kagayakase
Our dreams never end, so keep on shining
Let's start now GIANT KILLING!
for the right
For the right! Hold on tight!
hold on tight
my story…
My story...
forever
Forever...
王子！　王子！王子！　王子！　王子！
I can't read him.
うむ…　よ　読めん
No, I mustn't think too much. If I do that, I'll be playing right into his hands.
いや　変に考えるな
その時点で向こうのペスだ
It's all yours, Prince. I'll admit that you're handsome if you score.
頼むぜ　王子様
ここで決めたら男前って認めてやるよ
Alright!
よっしゃ！
さすが王子！
Way to go, Prince!
決めた！
It's in!
Alright!
よっしゃ！
ナイス　ジノ！
Nice, Gino! You're kind of handsome!
うん！まあまあ男前！
くっそ！やりづれえ！
Damn, this is rough.
Prince is on form!
いやあ乗ってますよ　王子
１点目の赤崎へのスルパスといい
The through pass to Akasaki for the first goal, the free kick for our second one,
２点目のフリキックといい
and as for the third goal, it was also his pass that led to an opponent's handball.
３点目のＰＫも 王子のパスがハンドを誘いましたからね
ハッハハハ　ご覧よ　ザッキ
Look at this, Zaki. They're all in awe of me.
みんなが僕に酔っているよ
I think you're just in awe with yourself.
自分に酔ってんじゃないスか
はぁ…　試合中　やたらと集中力が消えるのと
If he was more serious, focused and defensive-minded,
守備への意識がもう少しあれば
he would certainly be a national player.
確実に代表に呼ばれてる逸材だってのに…
Ten minutes left, huh? We need to keep attacking till the end.
残り１０分か最後まで
ガツガツいくよ
カネやん
Kaneyan, go get Sakai.
堺呼んで！
Sera, substitution.
世良　交代えっ
For real?
マジかよ
お疲れ！　世良
Good job, Sera.
Damn, I'm so dumb!
クソ！おれ俺のバカ！
That time...
あん時…
せっかく　チャンスもらったのに
I finally got a goal-scoring opportunity...
もっと中で　パスもらってれば
If I had gotten the ball nearer to the centre, I would've had a better shot.
もうちょっと　まともにシュトに行けたのに
いや 十分よくやってたぜ　世良
It's okay, you did good enough, Sera.
How was it good enough, Sano?
どこがスか　佐野さん？！
俺　フォワドなんですもん
I'm a forward!
A forward needs to score!
ゴル決めなきゃフォワドじゃないっスよ！
I want to score...
ゴル決めて
and celebrate it in the sparkly stadium!
あのキラキラって中でパフォマンスしたいんスよ
世良！　世良！世良！　世良！
And then, I'll do a back flip!
バク宙とかしちゃって
え？　世良バク宙できんの？
Wait, you can do a backflip?
Not right now, but I'm practicing!
できないっス練習中っス
Ah...I see.
あ…　そう
The last time I scored, we lost.
前　ゴルした時はチムが負けてたし
That is why I wanted to score and make it count today.
今日こそ　バッチリ決めてやろうと思ってたのに
I want to go out again.
もう１回出たい
あっ！　なんでサッカって　１回交代するともう出られないんスか
Why can't you go back in when you've been swapped out in soccer?!
You can swap as many times as you want in basketball and volleyball!
バスケとかバレは　何度も交代できんのに！
He's restless, eh?
めんどくさいヤツだなぁ
Damn it!
クッソ！
Go, ETU!
いけ！　ＥＴＵ！
Let's score a fourth one and finish the match up!
４点目取ってガッチリ勝とうぜ！
Continue down, Kiyokawa!
持ってけ　清川！
Run, run!
上がれ　上がれ！
うおっしゃ！
入れてこい　キヨ！
Pass it in, Kiyo!
よし！
Great!
Forget it!
させっかよ！
Saku.
サック
Oh man.
I thought I'd score a fancy one, since we're already three up...
３点目だから
華麗なの決めようと思ったのにな
惜しかったっスよ　王子
That's a pity, Prince. You could've gotten a hat-trick.
もうちょっとで　ハットトリック
Thanks, Baki.
ありがとう　バッキ
I guess that's it for today.
でも　今日は　もう終わりみたいだ
よっしゃ！
Yes!
Alright!
よっしゃ！
Consecutive wins!
連勝！
Yes!
やった！
What do you think, Yama? ETU won!
どうだい　山さん！勝ったぞ　ＥＴＵ
Y-Yes...
は　はい
わっしょい！
Hooray!
ETU. Their first victory on home soil.
ＥＴＵ　本拠地　初勝利ね
Alright!
よし！　よし！
This makes it a win and a loss for cup matches and a win and 3 losses for the league!
これでカップ戦１勝２敗
リグ戦１勝３敗
数字的にはまだまだ負けてるけど
I guess statistically we're still far behind...
But we're starting to get ourselves together. This is only the beginning!
調子は上向きだもんね
こっから　こっから！
Argh, I ended up pulling another all-nighter.
う…結局　徹夜しちまった
えっと…
Yokohama's No.4 on defense... Here...
横浜の　４バックの　ここを…
No good. I've got to clear my head!
グッ…　駄目だ頭　シャキッとさせねえと
First he's laughing, now he's crying.
笑った後に泣きだした
He must be...
間違いなく　あいつは…
an abusive drunkard.
たちの悪い酔っ払いだ
A suspicious-looking person; gotta call the police.
不審者　不審者１１０番しねえと
No! I'm not suspicious!
おっ！ふ　不審者じゃありません！
I'm a player for the club! I'm just happy, since I was out for quite some time.
俺はここの選手で
久々だったんで うれしくてつい…
Wait, he's...
あれ？　この人…
Who are you?
誰だっけ？　お前
This is no good.
いやいやこんなことじゃ駄目だ元気よくいこう！元気よく！
Let's put some spirit into it! Spirit!
Morning!
ティッス！
You're noisy, Sera.
うっさいなぁ　世良さん
はははっ！元気をアピル！
That's my spirit!
A forward has to stay positive all the time.
やっぱりフォワドは次　次って　いかないとね
I mean, I finally got my chance to start!
せっかく　チャンスもらってんだから　…あ
Oh yeah, seems like Natsu's back.
うん？　…あ　戻ってきたみたいっスよ　ナツさん
He will be joining in for practices from today onwards.
今日から練習参加だって
A-Are you serious?
ヘッ？　…マ　マジで？
ええっ　寝坊してる分際で
Weren't you sleeping like a log? How could you have met Natsu?
いつ夏木さんに会ったのよ？
In the morning. I saw him rolling around on the grass.
早朝…　なんか芝の上　転がってたあ…？
He said that he couldn't wait, so he came over as soon as the sun rose.
居ても立っても居らんなくなって日の出とともに出てきたんだって
確かに　夏木さんならやりかねない
That's definitely something he would do.
I've been guessing ever since he first called me over...
前に　電話であいさつされた時から思ってたけど…
He's a weirdo, isn't he?
あいつ変だろ　有里
I don't think he wants to hear that from someone who's still in bed when practice has already begun.
練習始まるってのに布団の中にいる達海さんに言われたくないと思うけど…
早くしなさいってば　もう！
Get up already!
Alright, alright.
はい　はい
Sheesh, why do I have to babysit you everyday?!
まったく！世話のかかる人なんだから！
That weirdo Natsuki...
夏木…
あんなヘンテコ野郎が
He only played half a season due to an injury last year, but he still ended up as ETU's top scorer.
昨シズンケガで半分しか出てないのに
ＥＴＵで　一番　点取った男か
My daughter wanted to see me grace the pitch.
娘が　俺の活躍　見たがっててさ
Apparently, I'm her hero.
パパはヒロだから
あ…　ナツさん
Natsu...
Yo, Akasaki.
よう　赤崎！
Nice to meet you. It's been a while.
ああ　どうも　ごぶさたっス
That was some goal yesterday!
ナイスゴルだったな　昨日は
You've got good technique!
いいなあ お前は　テクニックがあっていいなあ
Right, Sera?
な　世良
チュ…　チュッス
Cheers...
せ…　世良じゃねえか！元気にしてたか？ちっとは背　伸びたか？
If it isn't Sera! How have you been?!
Have you grown a little?
He immediately went to what I'm self-conscious about.
いきなり人が気にしてる事を
He's as insensitive as ever.
相変わらず無神経すぎる
You're working hard, aren't you?
頑張ってんじゃねえか
オメエスタメンだしよ
You even made it into the starting line-up! You pushed Sakai down the pecking order, right?
堺さん押しのけてだろ？
やるなあ　お前
You're really something!
ああっ！いや　あの　違うんス　堺さんそういう意味じゃないんス
Sakai, I didn't mean it like that! I'm sorry!
ハハ　すいません分かったよ　もう
Alright, I got it!
He is way too insensitive.
やっぱり無神経すぎる
ったく！うっせえヤツが帰ってきたな
Man, that loud trumpet is back.
クロが言うと説得力ないよ
That doesn't sound credible when it's said by you, Kuro.
８か月ぶりだってのに不安とかないのか？　あいつは
He was out for eight months. Doesn't he feel uneasy about his position at all?
Other than the manager and Matsu, we're all here, huh?
お…　監督と松さん以外は　大体おそろいかな？
では　改めて
Right, then let me announce this again.
My name is Natsuki Yotaro.
夏木陽太郎！　めでたく今日から　ＥＴＵに復活します！
I'll be rejoining ETU with immediate effect!
We thought of adding more striking options last season, but we failed.
昨シズン　ウチはフォワドの補強に失敗しましてね
I guess you know about it, but we had an ex-national player for Argentina, Fernando.
まあ　知ってると思いますが
元アルゼンチン代表の　フェルナンドです
He couldn't settle down in Japan.
日本に　なじめないわ絶不調だわで
His morale was poor and he wasn't really outstanding.
ロクな働きをしなかった
And the reason we're on a tight budget this season is because his salary was too high.
ああ 今期ウチが貧乏なのは ヤツが高額すぎたからなんですけど
I know.
知ってるよん
That was how the season started, so the team was in bad shape.
シズン序盤からそんな感じだったんで
チムの状態は最悪だったんですが 
But we actually managed to stop the rot and get back on track.
意外と　ズルズルいかずに 踏みとどまれた
Natsuki was the one who scored in games we absolutely could not lose.
絶対に落とせない試合
ここぞの場面で決めてくれたのが　夏木です
He was doing so well that he might even have been a serious contender for top scorer,
得点王争いに絡めるんじゃないかってくらい絶好調だったんですが　
but he tore his knee ligament and had to withdraw from the team.
夏に　膝のじんたい靱帯やっちゃって　チムを離脱
その後のチムは大変でしたけどね
Ever since then, the season just went downhill.
But we somehow managed to avoid relegation with what we had left.
何とか残った戦力で １部に残留しまして
Natsuki couldn't wait and kicked balls around, which
worsened his knee and delayed his recovery by 2 months.
夏木は　その間に　我慢できずに けボル蹴って
悪化して２か月延長
バカでしょう？
Isn't that stupid?
He couldn't suppress his urge to play when he's with the team, so we sent him away from the club for his rehab.
本人が　みんなといると我慢できないって言うんで
チムと隔離して　リハビリさせてまして
この時期になったというわけです
Which is why it took so long.
Thanks, Macchan, for giving me a recap.
まっあんがと　松ちゃんおさらいできたよ
チワス！　監督！どうぞよろしくお願いします！
Hi, Manager!
Nice to meet you! I'll work extra hard for the team!
チムに迷惑をかけた分 
I'll make up for the trouble I caused and help the team to win!
これからは身を粉にして勝利に貢献いたします！
Oh yeah, sure. Nice to meet you.
あ　はい　よろしく
Okay, players who're involved yesterday, proceed to do a warm-down. Then, we'll review yesterday's game.
じゃあ　昨日の出場者は軽めの調整で
その後　反省会
Kaneyan, take care of the reserves.
サブ組は　カネやん　よろしく
すぐ行くよ
Let's go.
H-He's so cool. Is Tatsumi always like that?
ク　クルだ…
いつもあんななのか？　達海さん
He's not really being cool, but that's how he always is.
いや　クルっていうか
いつも　あんな感じっスよ
I wonder if I'll be okay. I'm worried, Sera...
大丈夫かなあ　俺不安だよ　世良
I've been first-choice striker for most of the games this season.
今期の試合ほとんどが　フォワド　ワントップ
I was worried that I'll lose my place once Natsu comes back,
ナツさんが来たら　俺は出られないかと思ってたけど
but now that I think about it, he just came back from rehab, plus we have a new manager.
考えてみりゃ　ナツさんは
ケガ明けの上に 新監督なんだよな
On the other hand, I don't know if I'm good enough,
その点　俺は　こなせてるか分かんないけど　スタメンで出てるし
but I'm the first-choice now and I've scored a goal too.
ゴルも１点決めてる
I'm fine.
大丈夫だって！
自信持てって　俺！
Be more confident!
Sera, everyone's gone already.
世良さん　もう　みんな行ってますよえっ
Natsuki's doing individual training?
なんだ　夏木は別メニュか
That's normal, isn't it? It's his first day back.
そりゃそうでしょ初日なんだし
I'm glad that he's in good spirits.
よかったよ元気そうで
I'm envious of people who don't have any worries.
うらやましいよね　悩みがない人って
I got mobbed by female fans the other day and couldn't get out.
僕なんて　この前被女の子たちに車　囲まれちゃって
What are you bragging about?
何の自慢話っスか
I've never really seen him frowning before.
あいつが元気じゃないところ見たことないけどな
He's an optimist.
基本的にポジティブなヤツだからな
So even if he's worried, others wouldn't know.
悩んでても　周りに　そうは見えなかったりするんだろうが
Ever since Tatsumi became manager, he's been calling me a lot.
達海さんが監督になってから 夏木のヤツ
やたらと俺に電話してきたよえっ？
新チムが目指すサッカはどういうものか
What kind of playing style the new team is using...
How is training like...
練習はどうやるのかフォワドに求めてるものは何か
What is expected from the strikers...
It's the first time he's been out for eight months.
８か月もピッチを離れたのは初めてらしいからな
He says that he will need to start back from the bottom and push his way up.
マイナスからのスタトガムシャラにやるって言ってたぞ
His determination this season cannot be looked down upon.
今期のあいつは　気合いが半端じゃなさそうだぜ
You guys have to be on your toes.
負けてらんねえな　お前ら
I won't lose!
負けねえっスよ！俺だって　フォワドなんだ！
I am a striker too!
よく言ったぞ　世良！
Well said, Sera.
I'm proud of you.
偉いぞ！
な　なんで茶化すんスか
Why are you mocking me?
トクさん　俺もあっちで練習したい
Toku, I want to practice with them.
駄目だむちゃお前　すぐ無茶するから
Nope, you'll go overboard again.
I wanted to put up a good performance in front of him.
こっちは少しでもアピルしときたいのに
おわっ！　見てる！
He's looking at me!
Toku, send me a cross.
トクさん　ちょっと長いボル蹴ってよ　動きだしの感覚つかみたいんでおい！
I want to get the feel of running again.
Hey!
Give me a high one!
バウンド高めで！
Oh well... Don't push yourself!
しゃあねえな
無理すんなよ
Watch this.
見－てろーつ
S-See that?!
みっ　見たかっ！ヘヘ！
So about the starting line-up for the next game against the Mariners...
あ…　み　見てねえ…
He...
He wasn't looking!
コラ　夏木！
Hey, Natsuki!
I thought he just got back from rehab!
ど　どこがケガ明けだよ
What do you think you're doing?!
何やってんだ　お前！もうボル蹴らせねえぞ！
I won't let you kick any more balls.
危ねえだろ
That was dangerous.
I'm screwed. Can I still retain my position?!
ヤベエ　俺　レギュラ大丈夫か？
You've got find the way to believe
carry on and carry on
Carry on and carry on
Till you can see tomorrow
I'll say 「never look back「
I'll say “never look back”
追い風を待って
oikaze o matte
Wait for the tailwind
そうchanceをのがすなら
sou chance o nogasunara
そう chance を逃すなら
And if you missed the chance
自分が風になれ no fears no tears
jibun ga kaze ni nare
自分が風になれ
Become the wind yourself
no tears,Yes Let it go！
No fears! No tears! Yes! Let it go!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Stay gold!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
限界追い越せ
genkai oikose yuke
限界追い越せ行け
Surpass your limits and go!
行け キツイほど
kitsui hodo heart in red
キツイほど　heart in red
The harder it is the redder your heart will be!
heart in red
Go on！(Stay cool！）
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
Go on！(We'll go！)
We'll go!
あすは見えない だから
asu wa mienai dakara
あすは見えないだから
Because we can't see into the future
It's time to go
It's time to go yamerarenai
It's time to go やめられない
So it's time to go. We can't quit!
やめられない
Get tough！Get tough！ Get tough！
Get tough!
Get tough！(Stay gold！)
Get tough! Get tough!
Get tough！(We'll go！)
Stay gold!
共に乗り越えて 行け
We'll go!
tomo ni norikoete yuke
共に乗り越えて行け
Let's get through it together
見えるか It's daybreak there
mieruka It's daybreak there
Can you see that it's daybreak there?
Go on！(Stay cool！) Go on！(We'll go！)
Go on! Go on!
Stay cool!
We'll go!
予測できないだから
yosoku dekinai dakara
The future is unpredictable
It's time to go
It's time to go tomerarenai
It's time to go 止められない
So it's time to go. We can't stop!
How inconsistent can he be?
I guess some new pressure is needed.
Another game without a goal.
I'll get benched sooner or later!
I'm screwed!